This is a silver play button
and what this represents
is a bit like getting your
blue belt in Brazilian jujitsu, which
is the first colored belt you get after
being
a white belt. Now, the blue belt
is quite impressive because the white belt
is the
easiest place to quit.
Under 100,000 subscribers
is the easiest place to give
up and say, "This doesn't work."
But I'm afraid for many of you watching
this, the
option to not have a YouTube channel
is a very foolish one just with
the current landscape. Got AI,
we've got people getting laid off from
their jobs,
we've got people no longer needed,
people sitting in employment thinking,
"Wow, am
I going to be needed by this business in a
few years?
What am I going to do?"
And one of the best ways you can protect
yourself is to
grow and create a YouTube channel.
Now, first things first,
I have two YouTube channels, one
that has nearly half a
million subscribers.
That's a brand account,
and I made the mistake of years
trying to be famous
and talk about popular things to get
millions of views.
And you may have seen the creatine gummies
video that I did recently that got
millions of views. It paid me £3,500.
Once I paid my editor
and the testing for all the gummies
that I'd send off to
Eurofins,
about broke even for a few million views.
Whereas the channel you're watching me on
right now is very different to that.
This channel is about operating a
business.
So I see this channel as an employee
that works for me, and that employee works
around the clock finding people that
are perfect for me and showing them my
content, like you in this video right now.
And YouTube's probably found you because
there's a part of you inside your brain
that wants to start on YouTube.
And I wouldn't even say
that you don't know how.
You just haven't done it. Now,
throughout this video,
I'm going to tell you about a
silver play button course
that I've put together,
and it helps people start and
grow on YouTube.
It's only a few hundred dollars,
which you might think means it's
crap, but it's not. It's just new.
I've only probably helped about 400
businesses
get onto YouTube, and I still think
that I have a lot to learn in this niche,
so
I'd rather let people in for less money.
But anyway, you can check
that out whenever you're watching this
video.
First things first,
if you operate a business,
you have an unfair advantage on
YouTube. And what I mean by that
is there are so many influencers
and people out
there that need millions of views to keep
the lights on.
However, for many of you,
if you're in a position where you just
need to get a few
clients, you can do very well.
And what I'm going to do
is I'm going to show you
this. So to prove this to you,
I've only posted once on
YouTube this week,
but I get an email from RevTrack saying
that I've got
1,132 clicks and 909 unique leads.
So I would say that's 909 email addresses
and several of those people have clicked
on separate things. Now,
going to blow your mind a little bit as
well here,
hopefully.
I track every single link on YouTube
and these are going to be purchases
that come just from YouTube. So
if they go into a lead magnet
and buy further down
the line, this doesn't track them.
But I want to show you some of my best
performing videos on this smaller YouTube
channel. So if you look here, this video,
3rd of the 3rd, so just over a month
ago, $49,000. This one $23,000, $20,000,
$12,000, $10,000. That's not from views,
that's from clients.
Now, when you get clients, first of all,
they could be repeat purchases.
Second of all,
they could end up referring people.
Third of all,
you could end up using their progress to
help get new people in
there.
There's even going to be people
that you get on as clients that bring you
more clients. And the truth is,
I've got 1.4 million followers on
Instagram, 1.8
million on TikTok,
1.2 million on Facebook.
If I had to get rid of all of them,
I would keep this small little YouTube
channel
that to the blind eye could make it seem
like I'm falling off.
So at the moment,
I'm only getting 6,000 views a day.
I don't even have this channel monetized.
If we go look at my channel in person,
you could say, "James, your videos barely
break 5,000 views a video."
But that's okay because
5,000 views to a lot of people can seem
like not a lot.
But to me, 5,000, if I get 10% of
that on my email list each day,
put them through different automations
and sell them different offers,
I'm going to
do incredibly well. And this
is how I want you to start looking at
YouTube.
So straight away,
if you operate a business, this
is amazing.
So I made a video for a bit of fun with a
garage nearby
to me where we fit a titanium exhaust in
my car.
And I was chatting to Raz, the guy here.
I was saying to him, "Hey mate,
tell me this.
If someone was to watch you on a YouTube
channel fitting this exhaust into a car,
you could maybe be looking at one person
per 500 views." Now that means if a video
gets 5,000 views, he could get 10 leads.
If those 10 leads equate to seven people
getting an exhaust fitted, he's going to
do pretty well. This
is a full titanium system for a GT3.
This ended up costing about £13,000.
So his cost per acquisition could mean
£13,000, granted, not
all of it is profit, per 500 views.
That's how we need to start looking at
YouTube.
It's a place to operate a business.
Whereas if we go to someone, Mr.
Who's the Boss, for instance. Yeah,
he's got 22 million subscribers,
but he needs
to get huge amounts of views on his
content. Let's have a look.
3 million, 6 million, 5 million,
4 million, 2 million, 2 million, 2
million. Now, although this
is great for him and I'm sure he's doing
really well,
there's also an element of becoming famous
and becoming an influencer to pay
the bills is pretty exhausting.
Not to mention you give up a lot of
privacy, you
get haters online,
you get loads of negative comments.
If I said to you,
you could have half a million subs
or you could have 50,000.
I'm pretty much asking you,
do you want to make money
or do you want to be famous?
And I'm someone that's done both
and I'd say make money.
Yeah,
being well known can have its benefits
here and there.
You get some free stuff here and there.
You get sent some clothes.
But if I'm completely honest with you,
my big channel has done maybe
30 million views. Let's have a look.
Cool.
But the small channel I think has only
done about three.
Let's have a look at this for a second.
3 million views.
So here's a crazy stat.
I've nearly made $2 a view.
$5 million, two years, 3 million views,
$2 a view. It's crazy.
That's much better than YouTube would ever
pay me.
Now there's one more thing I'm going to
show you. I did a live stream.
When was this? November 24.
I haven't looked at this beforehand,
by the way.
Now there's eight views every 48 hours.
There's four views a day.
But out of those four views every day,
they're watching for 20 minutes each.
So if I said I could get four people every
day to watch 20 minutes of your
content that was done in November last
year, you'd go, "Wow, that's pretty good
that." That's from November.
It's six months old.
Then if I go through to the videos
and I try and find the long form version
of
this. Here you go. This
is the actual published version. 21 views.
So it's getting 10 views a day as well.
Same video, just one's posted live,
one's posted as another one.
10 people a day watching 15 minutes.
There are hours of my content being
consumed every single day that I
posted over six months ago. These
are people that are ending up in my
sales funnel, getting my automations,
growing my brand.
And every time I feed this YouTube channel
another video, the whole
ecosystem grows.
And some people will be drawn in by this
video today, then they'll
watch something else
and they'll go into another one.
As far as an employee,
YouTube doesn't take holidays,
doesn't need time off, works
around the clock,
proactively wants all of your videos to do
very, very, very well.
This is the best tool that
is being underutilized in the world
right now. And all you need to do
is turn your camera on and try and
help people. That's it.
And then you can give them stuff for free
or you can give
them stuff that costs money. What a job.
I don't think the window for doing this
is going to close
forever in the next three years because I
don't think AI is actually as good as
what people say. It's great,
but it's like Google search just got
amazing.
But I do think that within the next year
everyone's going to realize they
need to go to YouTube, that this
is the place to future proof your income,
your profession, your brand, everything.
And this is only going to get a lot harder
with more competitors coming to this
space.
So there's the silver play button course
in the description.
If you click the link from this video,
I will also honor you with 100% money back
guarantee.
If that course isn't enough to get you
started and start your business
online, I'll refund you in full.
So there's two outcomes from the end of
this
video. Well, I'll give you three. One,
you ignore my advice, you don't start on
YouTube. Two,
you become a silver play button expert
and you start.
Or three, you end up clicking here
and watching the next video
that comes up on the
channel because you're already killing it
on YouTube.
Either way, I hope you pick wisely
and hope to see your content on YouTube
soon.
Bye-bye.